All right. So, now that you've got your
website set up and you've got your
developer tools enabled, it's time to
figure out how they work. So, the way we
do that, um, the way you open your
developer tools is you use two fingers
and you click or you can hit command
option I
and that will pull up this toolbar at
the bottom and it's a whole bunch of
developer tools. So, there are four tabs
that we're going to use. And so, I'm
going to start on the left and just work
my way to the right. So, the first one
is this elements tab. This is helpful
for when you're looking at HTML. You can
see that it pulled in our HTML exactly
as we wrote it on our other page. And as
we hover over each HTML element, it'll
highlight it on the page. So, we know
that inside of our body element, there's
the text hello world. Something fun you
can do with this tab, and this works on
any website, is you can doubleclick and
you can change the text here. So, if I
was on um microsoft.com, I could come in
and inspect it and change how the page
shows up. Um so, this you can see it
highlights our HTML. And that that's
mostly what you'll use this elements tab
for is figuring out how your HTML is
working. You can test some styling here.
We probably won't use this tab very
often, but it is a tab we might possibly
use, so I wanted you to be aware of it.
The tab we're going to use the most
often is the console tab. So, this is
our console tab, and you can type into
the console and hit enter. And so, this
is where all of the errors you have when
something crashes in your code,
JavaScript is going to create an error.
So, I just typed out ASDF and a whole
bunch of letters and it said that's an
error. That doesn't work. That's not
accurate code. So, this is a great place
to look if you're having problems and
your code isn't running as you expect.
The first place you want to look is in
your console. The other helpful thing
about the console is that you can type
code into it. So, if you remember back
to the intro to JavaScript video where I
talked about what JavaScript was, talked
about coding languages, and I said that
you can create a hello world message um
with one line of code. The terminal
actually allows you to write JavaScript.
So, we're going to write that one line
of code. So, I'm going to zoom in a
little bit so you can see my terminal.
Um, and I'm going to type console.log
and then open parenthesis hello world.
And then I'm going to close that. And
then I'm going to hit enter. And you can
see immediately below where I typed the
JavaScript, it sent the message hello
world. Um, and now you've got your
you've run your first piece of
JavaScript. Um, so that's the console's
helpful because you can test any
JavaScript you want here. It'll also
show you all of your errors. The next
tab we want to talk about is this
sources tab. When you click on sources,
um, you're going to see that there's a
whole bunch of just a whole bunch of
information. The main thing you're going
to see is that this HTML document shows
up here and it's got a bunch of HTML.
On the left hand panel, you can see that
we're pulling from index.html.
We're going to talk more about this tab
when we get to debugging, but I wanted
you to be aware that it's here. If
you're overwhelmed right now, that's
totally okay. You don't need to
understand everything that's here. I
just want you to know that this tab is
here because we will be using it later.
And then the last tab we're going to
talk about is the network tab. This tab
is helpful for when we get to calling on
outside resources because it shows us
where those outside resources came from.
So if I zoom out just a little bit, um
you can see that I requested two
resources from this address. That's what
these numbers are. And it looks like
both of those resources came back. So
everything necessary to run this page
successfully showed up on this page.
Anytime I have a problem with my website
and something isn't loading properly,
I'll come check the network tab and that
will tell me um what's loading and
what's not. So again, just a quick
summary. Elements tab, it's where you
look for problems. If you have problems
with your HTML, console tab, if you have
problems with your JavaScript, this is
where you're going to look. Sources tab
is when you want to walk through your
code, and we'll talk more in depth in
debugging. And network tab is when
something isn't loading on your page
properly. This is the tab you're going
to want to check. All right, thanks for
watching.